# RATNESH KUMAR

E-mail: ratnesh567@rediffmail.com Contact: +91-8102966901

Address: Flat No-3C, Plot No-132, Road No-1, Basant Vihar, Harmu Housing Colony, Harmu, Ranchi, Jharkhand India. 834002.

## **SENIOR MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL**

Over 15 years' experience in developing and executing marketing strategies with the unique ability to understand the ongoing market scenario and customers trends using exceptional marketing communication skills

A business leader, marketing & customer service professional with a high level of business acumen and experience in leading operation, B2B & B2C marketing. Track record of driving sales into new markets and accounts whilst developing successful key account and product strategies; Lead role in all facets of bid management and contract negotiations.

## Areas of Excellence Include:

Developing New Business Mapping and Tapping Key Clients Growing Revenue & Profit

Techno Commercial Operations Motivating & Developing Team Leading Change

#### Objective Statement: -

Desire to join a fast paced growing firm that offers a constructive workplace to develop brand strategies, initiate strategic alliances, promote new products, and interact with new clients in order to develop sustained business for the organization.

#### ■ Professional Experience

L.T. ELEVATOR PVT. LTD. 2018 - Present Branch Manager (Jharkhand)

Location: Ranchi Jharkhand

ECE INDUSTRIES LTD. 2016 – 2018
 Area Manager (Sales & Operation)
 Location: Ranchi Jharkhand

Klaus Multiparking Systems Pvt. Ltd. 2015 - 2016
 Branch Head (Sales & Marketing North)

Location: Delhi NCR

Kinetic Hyundai Elevator & Movement Technologies Ltd.
 2011 – 2015

Dy. Manager (Sales & Marketing)

Location: Delhi NCR

Schindler India Pvt. Ltd. 2010 – 2011
 Sr. Account Executive (New Installation)

Location: Jaipur, Rajasthan

Kinetic Escalator & Elevator Ltd. 2006 – 2010
 Asst. Manager (Sales & Marketing)
 Location: Delhi NCR

Johnson Lifts Pvt. Ltd. 2004 - 2006 Sales Trainee for Service Contract Location: Delhi NCR

Devangana Associate 2003
 Sales Executive

Location: Agra, Utter Pradesh

## ■ Marketing Activities:

- Managed entire product marketing cycle Planning and applying the use of various sales strategies.
- Prepared the pricing strategy of the product.
- Negotiate with customers and clients on behalf of firm.
- Direct all meetings and produced presentations for clients.

## ■ Team Work:

- Worked hard as a team and as a good leader.
- Motivated the subordinates to work hard by assisting them.

# ■ Educational Qualifications:

- Bachelor's degree in Marketing Management (BMM)
- 10+2 form (BIEC) Bihar Intermediate Education Council Patna
- 10th From (CBSE) Central Board of Secondary Education

#### ■ Current Location

Ranchi Jharkhand

# ■ Personal Details:

• Father's Name : Sri A K Singh

Date of birth : 4th July'1980
Marital Status : Married

• Language Known : Hindi & English.

#### ■ Soft Skills

Microsoft Office and Internet Application

Ratnesh Kumar